<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Website of Buck Shlegeris.
</description>
    <link>http://shlegeris.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://shlegeris.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Should we encourage price discrimination based on income?</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s a crazy half-baked economics idea:&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/09/03/tax-percentiles.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/09/03/tax-percentiles.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Printers and price discrimination</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m reading “Modern Principles of Economics” by Alex Tabarrok and Tyler Cowen. I’m really enjoying it—it’s engagingly written and even though I’ve learned most of the material before, I keep learning fun little things.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/09/03/printers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/09/03/printers.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Privilege and polite disagreement</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content warning/TLDR: It’s usually unreasonable to demand that people calmly discuss topics which are personally charged to them. However, I think that it’s praiseworthy to be able to discuss these topics, and I want people to be better at not thinking of their political enemies as monsters. In this post I say that people should consider the possibility that they are wrong about things.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/30/white-dudes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/30/white-dudes.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Armchair Economist on moral philosophy</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I read a chapter of The Armchair Economist today. It’s an engagingly written book.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/24/armchair.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/24/armchair.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dumb ideas</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I often have ideas to do things that I know everyone else probably thinks are stupid. But I often like my dumb ideas. Using the inside view, my ideas seem very reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/16/dumb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/16/dumb.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using formatting in writing</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;When I’m writing, I often find myself wanting to use formatting to express myself. For example, I like using bold font to emphasize my most important sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/formatting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/formatting.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My advice to people about to attend bootcamps</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;An EA who’s going to be attending a bootcamp in a few months emailed me a few days ago asking for advice. Here is an edited version of our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/bootcamp-attendees.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/bootcamp-attendees.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My advice on studying algorithms</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Software engineering interviews often ask whiteboard algorithms questions. Here’s my advice on how to study for them. (My credentials on this topic are:  I have passed a lot of whiteboard interviews, including at Google and Apple;  as part of my job I prepare programmers for these algorithm interviews; I have conducted more than 200 technical interviews on programmers with a very wide variety of backgrounds.)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/algorithms.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/08/14/algorithms.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Counterfactual reasoning</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a kind of thought process which I enjoy, which I think is pretty core to EA. It’s a particular approach to answering questions of the form “should I do X”. It involves counterfactual reasoning, a bunch of basic microeconomics, and careful attention to your values.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/07/31/counterfactuals.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/07/31/counterfactuals.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do people date less if they have easy access to porn?</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s some evidence that access to pornography decreases sexual assault and child abuse. The proposed mechanism is that horny people get to watch more porn, and this makes them less sexually frustrated, which makes rape seem less tempting. Analogously, violent movies seem to reduce violence in the short term. Slate Star Codex discusses both of these effects &lt;a href=&quot;http://slatestarcodex.com/2013/06/22/social-psychology-is-a-flamethrower/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. In particular, &lt;a href=&quot;https://maggiemcneill.files.wordpress.com/2012/04/pornography-rape-and-the-internet.pdf&quot;&gt;this linked paper&lt;/a&gt; considers all the objections that I’d thought of and seems pretty reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/07/29/porn.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/07/29/porn.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

