<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Website of Buck Shlegeris.
</description>
    <link>http://shlegeris.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://shlegeris.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Why are less intelligent people more racist?</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Epistemic status: I think there’s a 75% chance that less intelligent people have at least a 20% higher relative probability of agreeing to racist or segregationist claims like “blacks tend to be lazy”. I think my explanation of this phenomenon is probably roughly right. I don’t think my explanation is very nonobvious to people with the right background knowledge; I just applied primitive evo psych reasoning to the problem and was happy with what came out.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2017/03/13/racist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2017/03/13/racist.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hash map implementations in practice</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to Kent Ross for finding several of the details which I list here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2017/01/06/hash-maps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2017/01/06/hash-maps.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Wild speculations on the balance of pain and pleasure</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Epistemic status: mad speculation, mixed with math that’s so much fun that I find it hard to believe it’s useful. I’m serious about thinking these questions are important, I’m much less confident in any of my answers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/12/30/pain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/12/30/pain.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A dynamic programming algorithm for the Gini coefficient</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There’s a very simple &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;O(n)&lt;/script&gt; DP algorithm for calculating the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gini_coefficient&quot;&gt;Gini coefficient&lt;/a&gt; of a sorted list. The code for it honestly looks almost simpler than the naive formula. Code is at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/12/29/gini.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/12/29/gini.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimal resource allocation between manufacturing and research</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks heaps to Ben Weinstein-Raun, without whose comments this post would have a confident and wrong conclusion. Thanks also to Chen-Yu Yang for spotting a typo.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/26/research.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/26/research.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advice on whether you should get a PhD in engineering</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Lewis Collins, who I incidentally first met when I was eleven, recently asked me for some advice about whether he should get do a PhD in mechatronic engineering. I ended up writing about PhDs more generally. I’m interested in the thoughts of people who have experience with this stuff. Here’s what I wrote.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/13/phd.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/13/phd.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Building a search engine for data structures</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I &lt;a href=&quot;https://scalaebythebay2016.sched.org/event/7iUk/automatic-composition-of-fast-data-structures&quot;&gt;presented at Scala By The Bay&lt;/a&gt; about my project to build a search engine for data structures. I’ve deployed the project at &lt;a href=&quot;http://ds.shlegeris.com&quot;&gt;ds.shlegeris.com&lt;/a&gt;; you can play with it there. You can also read the source code &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bshlgrs/data-structure-composer&quot;&gt;on Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/13/ds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/11/13/ds.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Poor college graduates do much better than rich high-school dropouts</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2014/10/18/poor-kids-who-do-everything-right-dont-do-better-than-rich-kids-who-do-everything-wrong/&quot;&gt;This article from 2014&lt;/a&gt;, with the provocative title “Poor kids who do everything right don’t do better than rich kids who do everything wrong” is terrible. It makes a shitty and misleading graph, and makes a variety of nonsensical judgements based on it.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/23/poor-college-graduates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/23/poor-college-graduates.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Left-libertarianism</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I know a lot of people who identify as left-libertarians, or bleeding-heart libertarians, or whatever. Scott argued for this position &lt;a href=&quot;slatestarcodex.com/2013/12/08/a-something-sort-of-like-left-libertarianism-ist-manifesto/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Gary Johnson has &lt;a href=&quot;http://bleedingheartlibertarians.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/GaryJohnson1-1.jpg&quot;&gt;posed wearing a Bleeding Heart Libertarians shirt&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of rationalists and EAs seem to think of this as the political position of utilitarians who are aware of the benefits of free markets but also the costs of externalities and inequality.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/20/libertarians.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/20/libertarians.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optimal redistribution with a flat tax</title>
        
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have a bunch of people who differ only in their wage &lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;w&lt;/script&gt;. Everyone has utility logarithmic in their consumption. As the government, you want to promote welfare by redistributing consumption. You decide to do this by instituting a flat tax and using it to fund a universal basic income.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/07/optimal-tax.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://shlegeris.com/2016/10/07/optimal-tax.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>

